...and "twice" is the only way to live!
You Only Live Twice is a action, thriller,
adventure film directed by Lewis Gilbert.
A mysterious spacecraft captures Russian and American space capsules
and brings the two superpowers to the brink of war.
James Bond investigates the case in Japan and comes
face to face with his archenemy Blofeld.
James Bond, played by Sean Connery.
Aki, played by Akiko Wakabayashi.
Kissy Suzuki, played by Mie Hama.
Tiger Tanaka, played by Tetsuro Tamba.
Mr. Osato, played by Teru Shimada.
Helga Brandt, played by Karin Dor.
You Only Live Twice is a 1967 spy film and the fifth film in the
James Bond series produced by Eon Productions.
The film's screenplay was written by Roald Dahl, and was loosely
based on Ian Fleming's 1964 novel You Only Live Twice.
It is the first of three Bond films to be directed by Lewis Gilbert, and is the first Bond film to discard most of Fleming's
plot, using only a few characters and locations from the book as the background for an entirely new story.
You Only Live Twice stars Sean Connery as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond, who is dispatched to Japan after
American and Soviet spacecraft vanish mysteriously, each nation blaming the other amidst the Cold War.
Bond travels to a remote island to find the perpetrators, and comes face-to-face with Ernst Stavro Blofeld, the head of SPECTRE, an organisation that is
working for the government of an unnamed Asian power, implied to be China, to provoke war between the United States and the Soviet Union.
Although the character Blofeld played a role in previous films, You
Only Live Twice is the first film to depict him visually.
During the filming in Japan, it was announced that Sean Connery would leave the role of Bond, but after one film's
absence, he returned in 1971's Diamonds Are Forever and later in 1983's non-Eon Bond film Never Say Never Again.
You Only Live Twice received positive reviews and grossed over $111 million
(equivalent to $1 billion in 2024) in worldwide box office.
However, it was the first Bond film to see a decline in box-office revenue, primarily owing to the oversaturation of the spy
film genre from Bond imitators, including a competing Bond film, Casino Royale, from Columbia Pictures (1967).
The Bond series continued with On Her Majesty's Secret Service in 1969,
the first film without Sean Connery in the lead role.
The film explores themes of island, japan,
assassin, london, england, helicopter.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.